Idan Joshua Garay

A highly motivated software engineer with a strong desire to advance to the role of principal software engineer, I am dedicated to continuous learning to further refine my skills and expertise in the field. A quick learner with a solid foundation in programming principles and techniques.

garayidan@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/idan-joshua-garay-1a4 657176/ github.com/ldan-Garay idanjoshua.com/

EXPERIENCE

KODA Kollectiv — Frontend Software Engineer

JULY 2022 - JANUARY 2023

Integrated Apple Pay with StripeJS for payment feature

Integrated Apple for omni-authentication as an alternative login

Integrated Admob to a search result feature to display ads

Implemented web components and features using Redux/RTK

Virtual Byte IT Solutions — Frontend Engineer Intern

MAY 2021 - AUGUST 2021

Developed forms and inputs with validation using Bootstrap, and react-hook-forms

Implemented web components with react hooks e.g. useReducer and

Implemented filtering and sorting data to help users find specific information

EDUCATION

University of San Carlos, Cebu, Philippines

JUNE 2019 - DECEMBER 2023

B.S. Computer Science

Bachelor's Coursework: Algorithms & Complexity, Programming Languages, Software Engineering, Pre-Calculus, Advance Calculus, Data Analytics, Object-oriented Programming, Data Structures, Databases, Programming I & II, Networking, System Analysis and Design, Web Development

EXPERTISE

Next.JS React Redux Webpack Typescript TailwindCSS HTML/CSS Git

SKILLS

Node

Interpersonal Communication

Problem-Solving

Teamwork

Attentive

CERTIFICATIONS

Shopee Code League 2022 -Participant

PROJECTS

Agglomerative Clustering with Sentiment Analysis — github.com/Idan-Garay/Twitter-Thesis-Project

The codebase of my thesis that implements Agglomerative Clustering with Sentiment Analysis

HandyHome — (React, Sequelize, JS, Context) qithub.com/Idan-Garay/HandyHome/tree/Admin-pages

A job marketplace web application for menial jobs where verified job seekers can form their own team for employers to see.

Sweet Surrender — (Laravel, PHP, Bootstrap) <u>github.com/Idan-Garay/Sweet-Surrender</u> (Laravel, PHP, Bootstrap)

A web application for a sweets and pastries business where the owner can display the products and track the inventory of the business.

TECH STACK

Proficient — React, Typescript, HTML/CSS, NextJS, TailwindCSS, AWS, Webpack, Node

Have used — Vue, Sequelize, Vercel, JQuery, PHP, GraphQL, Firebase, MySQL, C, Java, Python, Django